<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.1.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://karmanyaah.malhotra.cc/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://karmanyaah.malhotra.cc/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-11-05T01:18:34-05:00</updated><id>https://karmanyaah.malhotra.cc/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Karmanyaah Malhotra</title><subtitle>This is my personal website for experimentation and having a profile that I maintain on the WWW.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Site fixing</title><link href="https://karmanyaah.malhotra.cc/meta/2020/11/05/site-fixing.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Site fixing" /><published>2020-11-05T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-11-05T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://karmanyaah.malhotra.cc/meta/2020/11/05/site%20fixing</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://karmanyaah.malhotra.cc/meta/2020/11/05/site-fixing.html">&lt;p&gt;So I’m back to fixing my website now!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s 12:30AM EST right now and I finally got around to implement blogging on my site. I looked around at a bunch of Jekyll themes, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://hyde.getpoole.com/&quot;&gt;Hyde&lt;/a&gt; really stood out, except it hasn’t been maintained in forever with open Pull Requests and all that. I first found out about Hyde from David Tomaschik’s blog, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://systemoverlord.com/2017/03/19/got-and-plt-for-pwning.html&quot;&gt;GOT/PLT pwning page&lt;/a&gt; of which I’ll have to keep visiting until I finally memorize everything (I’m much closer to that rn).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hopefully I can get my site into a reasonably usable condition fixing the relatively cringe theme thinking about it nearly a year later. I’ll also work on fixing my CV setup ASAP so I can get all my grades, CTFs, and Science Olympiad ranks into an ordered format. Most importantly, I hope to be able to summarize it well enough since those are very important characteristics of my CV right now, but that won’t be the case forever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once I figure all of this out I can also get around to doing it on the bhscs blog and figure out how to get all our CTF writeups in there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;EOF&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Karmanyaah</name></author><category term="Meta" /><summary type="html">So I’m back to fixing my website now!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Intro to jekyll</title><link href="https://karmanyaah.malhotra.cc/meta/2019/12/21/intro-to-jekyll.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Intro to jekyll" /><published>2019-12-21T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-12-21T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://karmanyaah.malhotra.cc/meta/2019/12/21/intro%20to%20jekyll</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://karmanyaah.malhotra.cc/meta/2019/12/21/intro-to-jekyll.html">&lt;p&gt;Got started with jekyll for my site today&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jekyll(super awesome should check out) wants me to put&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A banana is an edible fruit – botanically a berry – produced by several kinds of large herbaceous flowering plants in the genus Musa.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In some countries, bananas used for cooking may be called “plantains”,
    distinguishing them from dessert bananas. The fruit is variable in size, color,
    and firmness, but is usually elongated and curved, with soft flesh rich in
    starch covered with a rind, which may be green, yellow, red, purple, or brown
    when ripe.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Karmanyaah</name></author><category term="Meta" /><summary type="html">Got started with jekyll for my site today</summary></entry></feed>